<page id="estatisticas">
    <ident>$Ident: Sun 05, 2025 at 15:32 +0100</ident>
    <author>$Author: massimo.manghi $</author>
    <date>$Date: 2016-05-11 11:01:21 +0200 (Wed, 11 May 2016) $</date>
    <title>Conference Information</title>
    <headline>Conference Information</headline>
    <menu position="top">banner</menu>
    <menu position="right">home</menu>
    <content language="en">
        <title>About Erice</title>
        <headline>About Erice</headline>
        <pagetext>
            <section id="one">

                <div class="inner">
                    <header class="major">
                        <h1>Elements</h1>
                    </header>

                        <p>
                        According to a legend, Erice, son of Venus and Neptune, founded a small town on top of a 
                        mountain (750 metres above sea level) more than three thousand years ago. The founder of 
                        modern history-i.e. the recording of events in a methodic and chronological sequence as they 
                        really happened without reference to mythical causes - the great Thucydides (500 B.C.), 
                        writing about events connected with the conquest of Troy (1183 B.C.)  said:
                        </p>
                </div>
            </section>
            <blockquote>
        	"After the fall of Troy some Trojans on their escape from the Achaei on the sea towards the West
        	arrived in Sicily by boat and as they settled near the border with the Sicanians all together they
        	were named Elymi: their towns were Segesta and Erice". 
            </blockquote>
            <p>
        	This inspired Virgil to describe the arrival
        	of the Troyan royal family in Erice and the burial of Anchise, by his son Enea, on the coast below
        	Erice. Homer (1000 B.C.), Theocritus (300 B.C.), Polybius (200 B.C.), 
        	Virgil (50 B.C.), Horace(20 B.C.), and others have celebrated this
        	magnificent spot in Sicily in their poems. During seven centuries (XIII-XIX) the town of Erice
        	was under the leadership of a local oligarchy, whose wisdom assured a long period of cultural
        	development and economic prosperity which in turn gave rise to the many churches, monasteries
        	and private palaces which you see today. In Erice you can admire the Castle of Venus, the
        	Cyclopean Walls (800 B.C.) and the Gothic Cathedral (1300 A.D.).
        	</p><p>
        	Erice is at present a mixture of ancient and medieval architecture. 
        	Other masterpieces of ancient civilization are to be found in the neighbourhood: at 
        	Motya (Phoenician), Segesta (Elymian), and Selinunte (Greek). On the Aegadian Islands – theatre 
        	of the decisive nav al battle of the first Punic War (264-241 B.C.) - suggestive 
        	neolithic and paleolithic vestiges are still visible: the grottoes of Favignana, the carvings
        	and murals of Levanzo. Splendid beaches are to be found at San Vito Lo Capo, Scopello and Comino.
        	The rocky coast around Monte Cofano is another scenic place in Erice's surroundings: 
                every spot is located at less than an hour's drive from Erice.
            </p>
            <h4>Climate</h4>
            <p>
        	As Erice is situated on top of a mountain at an altitude of 750 metres, it is much cooler than
        	at sea level. Therefore, we would advise you to bring some warm clothing, and a windbreaker or 
        	anorak; the weather is rather unpredictable in Erice and the temperature can suddenly change.
            </p>
            <!-- highslide inline="teatro-piccola.jpg" full="teatro-grande.jpg" class="inlinephoto" />
        	<highslide inline="panorama-piccola.jpg" full="panorama-grande.jpg" class="inlinephoto" />
		<highslide inline="castello-piccola.jpg" full="castello-grande.jpg" class="inlinephoto" / -->
        </pagetext>
    </content>
 </page>
